# 今天大爷还做一个家庭版的
Today Daye is going to cook a homestyle
# 炒疙瘩
ChaoGeDa(Fried dough drops)
# 我先把面和上 和这面要硬一些
First of all, Kneading dough, the dough need to a bit harder
# 基本跟面条面是一样的
Almost same as the dough for making noodle
# 面就用我们的
You can use either
# 标准粉也行 高筋粉也行
Plain flour or bread flour
# 有的爱吃粗粮的
Someone would like to eat coarse grain
# 可以用棒子面 玉米面
So you can use cornflour
# 我要提醒的就是什么呢
What I want to remind you is
# 一定用开水烫一下（棒子面）
Remember to use boiling water when mixing flour (corn flour)
# 烫的硬一些 然后搁上
Mix until a bit hard, and then
# 三分之一或者四分之一的白面
Add ⅓ or ¼ of wheat flour
# 里边适当的少搁一点盐
Add a little bit salt
# 面和好了 好了
Is the dough kneaded already? Yes
# 我看这面有点多
I think the dough is a little bit too much
# 面和好了 我们饧一饧 盖块小屉布
Rest the dough after kneaded, cover a piece of cloth
# 下一项咱们备小料
Next, let’s prepare some ingredients
# 来点五花肉 根据自己的喜好可多可少
Pork belly, meats ration depends on your preference
# 把肉切成肉丁
Cut the meat into fine dice
# 这肉丁切小点 借味
Cut the dices a little smaller, so that lends flavor
# 肉切好了
The meat was cut
# 青蒜 豌豆 胡萝卜 葱头
Green garlic, pea, carrot, onion
# 肉丁 香菇 葱姜
Meat dice, shiitake mushroom, scallion and ginger
# 爱吃什么放什么 挺随意的
Just feel free to add what you like
# 这面呢 也饧好了
The dough has rested already
# 刚才我趁大妈没注意 我给揉了揉
I just kneaded it again when DaMa didn’t notice
# 特别滋润 又挺硬
Very glutinous, and hard
# 这个面有两种成型方式
This dough has two ways of forming
# 一种擀的厚一点 再切丁
One is roll out thicker and cut it into dice
# 切成厚片
Cut into thick slice
# 我们拖点面
Let’s cover some flour
# 但是擀它显得瓷实
It will be solid if we roll it
# 这个显得松软 省事儿这个
And this way will be soft, and easy
# 这个不能太大了
Don’t cut too big
# 太大了有时候煮的不好熟
It’s hard to cooked if it’s too big
# 吃的时候也费劲
Also hard to eat
# 准备一盆 要干
One basin of dry dough dices
# 还有一种 就跟擀面条一样
the other way just like make noodles
# 在家里做饭就是玩儿  什么玩儿呢
It’s fun to cook at home
# 你看跟过家家似的
Like playing house
# 要是大家没有时间 其实超市有卖的
If you don’t have time to make a dough, you can buy it in the supermarket
# 那个买回来煮的时候得多煮一会儿
But if you buy it in the supermarket, you need to cook longer
# 它那特别硬
Because it’s tough
# 这家里头有个大厨
It’s so happy, super happy
# 他就是幸福 幸福极了
To have a chef at home
# 撒点干面 摇
Sprinkle with some flour, shake it
# 下锅了啊 开了
Put in the pot
# 煮完了煮的时间稍微长一点
Cook a little longer
# 比面条要长一点
longer than cook noodles
# 面疙瘩马上就出锅了
Dough dices almost cooked
# 咱们现在开始炒菜 炒这料
Now we begin to fry the ingredients
# 还是一个 热锅凉油
Add oil after heat up the wok
# 这个时候的油稍微多一点 它香
We need a little more oil, assist aroma
# 先煸肉丁
Stir-fry the meat dice first
# 如果家里有老人这肉丁得浆一下
mash the meat if have old people at home
# 但是一般咱们吃就不用浆了
But we don’t need to mash
# 为什么 主要我们要肥瘦肉
Because the pork belly
# 也是有增香的一种效果
Can assist flavor
# 肉煸出点油来 葱姜也（出香味了）
Stir fry the meat with oil, and scallion and ginger also have aroma
# 胡萝卜 豌豆 出下水 焯了一下
Parboil the carrot and peas
# 煸炒
stir-fry
# 放材料
Add seasoning
# 酱油 这个色也是随着自己
Soy sauce, this color also according to your preference.
# 黄酒
Huangjiu rice wine
# 大爷搁盐还是猛
Daye love to add strong salt
# 别那么猛
Don’t add too much
# 一勺两勺 得三勺 两勺半
Two and a half spoon of salt
# 把葱头下去 葱头后下
And then put onion, put onion later
# 太晚了也不行 下早了也不行
But don’t too late also don’t too early
# 太早了它就炒老了  炒老了就不好吃了
It will be too old if you put early, then it will not delicious
# 搁点蚝油 胡椒粉
Some oyster sauce,some pepper
# 这个料炒得了
And we done the ingredient
# 大妈稍微给看着一点 我捞面
Dama will help me to look out, I’ll get some GeDa
# 二厨也扒拉两下 瞧瞧咱们挺专业的吧
Second chef also join the cook, look, we are professional, right
# 火大点儿没事
It’s okay to the heat a little higer
# 好了 这可太多了
Okay. This is too much
# 青蒜
Green garlic
# 搁点果仁行不行啊 可以 那才香啊
Can we put some nut? Of course
# 搁点花生碎 撒点芝麻
You can put some crushed peanut, or sesame
# 这个在锅里边稍微炒一炒
Stir-fry in the pot
# 因为它有面的淀粉
Because the starch of the dough
# 炒的时候黏黏糊糊的
It’s glutinous when you fry
# 然后最好锅底火大一点还带点嘎巴
And better to a bit heat up.
# 关火了 熟了
Okay we done
# 装盘
Serve
# 让大家看看 这是效果
Everyone look at it, this is result
# 这行了吧 可以了
All set? yes
# 大厨拿着是不是
Chef should hold it
# 家有大厨 就是幸福
It’s happy to have a chef at home
# 谢谢大爷
Thank you, Daye